<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>niko.</title>
    <link>https://aquamarine-heliotrope-618f98.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on niko.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Niko McCarty</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aquamarine-heliotrope-618f98.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://aquamarine-heliotrope-618f98.netlify.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aquamarine-heliotrope-618f98.netlify.app/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a science writer, editor and programmer in Cambridge, MA. Currently: Head of Media at New Science.
I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for essay ideas that would benefit young scientists, or expose them to new ways of thinking.
I write Codon, a newsletter about synthetic biology, CRISPR and biotechnology. My work has appeared in Retraction Watch, Scientific American, Forbes, The Counter and elsewhere. Prior to journalism, I was a scientist for 7 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Published Work</title>
      <link>https://aquamarine-heliotrope-618f98.netlify.app/published/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aquamarine-heliotrope-618f98.netlify.app/published/</guid>
      <description>Selected Pieces  Blogs about synthetic biology at Codon. Interactive autism drug tracker. Feature on two-photon holographic optogenetics. Feature on DNA-based food tracking. A technical proposal to engineer ribosomes to incorporate D-amino acids in living cells.  Scientific American  Mosquitoes See Red (Literally) when They Smell Human Breath (print issue) Newly Studied Proteins Expand CRISPR&amp;rsquo;s Editing Range (print issue)  The Counter  Foodborne diseases kill thousands of Americans each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYU Science Journalism Twitter Bias</title>
      <link>https://aquamarine-heliotrope-618f98.netlify.app/posts/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aquamarine-heliotrope-618f98.netlify.app/posts/post-1/</guid>
      <description>The verdict: Men and women who graduate from NYU&amp;rsquo;s SHERP program tend to have a similar number of Twitter followers. Let me explain how I know that.
A few months ago, while dreaming up story ideas for a health journalism course at NYU, I came across a study about gender disparities—in a medical journal. In that paper, researchers quantified the influence that male and female medical researchers exert on Twitter. The main finding: female medical researchers have a lower number of Twitter followers compared to their male colleagues, and this gap tends to widen as women progress in their careers and are promoted to higher tenure ranks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://aquamarine-heliotrope-618f98.netlify.app/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aquamarine-heliotrope-618f98.netlify.app/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
